<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on The Cauldron of Life</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on The Cauldron of Life</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.135.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 10:13:13 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Raise a Child to Raise Yourself</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/raising-a-child-to-raise-yourself/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 10:13:13 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/raising-a-child-to-raise-yourself/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m of the strong opinion that region, religion, language, caste, race, and like are all man-made barriers. It is a barrier that gives man a sense of false control. It makes things look limited, though in reality, it is limitless. We do not want to accept that we are no more significant than a stone or a leaf; we are just happening, and that is the purpose. These are all amplified reflections of the man’s ego. His belief in the I. The idea that I am important and things that happen to me are important. If you observe a little closer, you will realize that when you love someone, it’s because of YOU in that equation. When you feel bad about something, it is because of the I in the context. To humans, it is all about I. I don’t know if this is the case with other animals or if it is only a human phenomenon, but it must also have a purpose as it is given to us.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Kind of Vacation I Want</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/the-kind-of-vacation-i-want/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 19:23:33 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/the-kind-of-vacation-i-want/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been traveling a lot since my childhood. My parents fortunately had the genes of wanderlust which I inherited. They did it in their own way by planning trips around temple. Maybe it was their way of making it worth the salt. I nonetheless enjoyed it because it was all new to me.  I have a lot of memories from these trips. The long cozy train ride, the overnight cold road trips, the long queue of the temples in the heat, the first plane journey, the bluest beach of my life, the tallest waves I had ever seen or the tallest building to have ever existed.  Some of them were budget trips and some luxurious. In some I was on the beach while on some I was looking at the white snow. I can go on and on about all my experiences but what is the point? I wanted to emphasize to myself that I’ve travelled a good deal and seen a lot.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Would I Say Before Goodbye?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/what-would-i-say-before-goodbye/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 12:38:07 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/what-would-i-say-before-goodbye/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you know today is the last time you will see people you love and it’s a bye forever. Who would you want to see and what would your last words be for them?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m writing this on a plane. Sometimes I get afraid of the height and the reality that this could be the last ride of my life but yet I survive and keep going. I wanted to write down these thoughts and all the people I could think of in that last day. There were not many people to list down! Also this list is in not in any order but the order in which they came to my mind.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Living the Remote Life</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/living-the-remote-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 01:22:45 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/living-the-remote-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Life is confusing! Isn&amp;rsquo;t it? We envy what we don&amp;rsquo;t have, and what we have becomes worth pebbles. I started working remotely in 2017, way before when working from home was a thing. Friends and family were almost sure that I was unemployed and probably ran some scam racket and peddled drugs. They had no other answer on how I was staying at home, chilling and still getting a decent amount of money flowing into my bank account. 🤷‍♂️&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Question I Ask Myself on The Brink of 30</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/questions-i-ask-myself-on-the-brink-of-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 09:45:07 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/questions-i-ask-myself-on-the-brink-of-30/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Life is interestingly chaotic. We die for that which we don&amp;rsquo;t have and then get bored of that same thing when we get it. I sometimes feel that what we want is a pursuit of something. The struggle and hard work make us feel whole. In the journey, we forget everything and focus on achieving that goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This brings me to thinking - what do I want from life now? I have a loving family, a beautiful wife, a house to live in, a car that drives well, and now a child that won&amp;rsquo;t let me sleep(or let my wife sleep).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When your dog is not perfect 🐶</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/when-your-dog-is-not-perfect/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 21:39:48 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/when-your-dog-is-not-perfect/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Life is imperfect, and things usually don&amp;rsquo;t turn out how we want, and the same seems to have happened with me and my dog. They say that every dog has a different personality, but there are days when I feel I have been shortchanged for a bad apple. 😅&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may ask what&amp;rsquo;s wrong with my dog, but that&amp;rsquo;s for later. My dog is almost 3 years, and you may be asking why I am bringing this up. What does it have to do with life? I would say - a lot.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Retire at 30! Then What?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/retire-at-thirty-then-what/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2022 01:56:38 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/retire-at-thirty-then-what/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The dream of being financially free and retiring is dear to every working human, but if you ask them what they will do with their retirement, that is not clear. At least not to the majority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This creates a problem in fulfilling the dream. If we could clearly visualize what we wanted, we could undoubtedly get it. I think that&amp;rsquo;s true. Not because of some cosmic power that would bring us closer to the goal but because clarity empowers action.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Kills Communication?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/what-kills-communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 14:09:16 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/what-kills-communication/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have always wondered why it&amp;rsquo;s complicated to talk to a person close to us but so exciting to open up to a random stranger we just connected with? We always emphasise that communication is the key to any relationship, but we end up struggling for a conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fear-of-being-judged&#34;&gt;Fear of Being Judged&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we talk to someone we already know, we fear being judged. People always judge! Maybe we are trying to be better, and our past actions do not coincide with the newer self.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Human Networks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/human-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 21:46:53 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/human-networks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Networking must have been essential to human evolution. It is a tool that enables us to do things that we cannot do alone. When humans were still evolving, networking was a necessity, but today it&amp;rsquo;s a skill we must have to prosper in our community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-do-you-need-to-get-good-at-building-networks&#34;&gt;What do you need to get good at building networks?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I want to explore a set of questions sitting in the back of my head. Why do we connect with some people and not with others? What qualities make us feel that it&amp;rsquo;s worthwhile relating to someone? And more importantly, what qualities should a person possess so that other human beings desire them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Letter of Love</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/letter-of-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:20:41 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/letter-of-love/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello Pikachu,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you know a sure way to tell if someone is in love? In love, a person becomes hopelessly romantic and crave a medium to let it out. They express their emotions through poetry, songs and letters and I&amp;rsquo;m writing this to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are the &lt;del&gt;piece&lt;/del&gt; peace of me that I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking for. I&amp;rsquo;ve been blessed with an almost perfect life and you just took away the almost. Maybe it was my heart that didn&amp;rsquo;t let it be perfect? Or maybe it was yours that was designed to fit in that cage better? I don&amp;rsquo;t know but you did well, taking mine away and leaving me yours.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Last Breath</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/the-last-breath/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 23:30:23 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/the-last-breath/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is said that we are ignorant and we have stopped thinking about the inevitable end but I think we haven&amp;rsquo;t. Instead, I believe we understand it&amp;rsquo;s certainty and we avoid spending energy thinking about it. We know that an end will come but we don&amp;rsquo;t like to imagine when or how painful it would be to die but we are sure that it will.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grief is a natural response to a personal loss. When you lose someone who is never going to come back the same way it can be devastating. Death hurts and grief is a natural response to it. Shed tears, dump your heart out and do everything that needs to be done. Such a loss can be shared with other loved ones, who are grieved by your grief. Lucky are those who have someone around them who can share their grief, otherwise, to the world, it&amp;rsquo;s all a mocking game, generally. Blessed are those who feel pained from the pain of others. They are the saviours, saving this world from becoming an orphanage. Only this true care for another being is what makes a family otherwise everyone is selfish to some degree and then what else should I call this world if not an orphanage.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Capitalism is Not Life</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/too-much-capitalism-is-bad-for-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 22:29:32 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/too-much-capitalism-is-bad-for-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I completed reading &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sapiens:_A_Brief_History_of_Humankind&#34;&gt;Sapiens: A Brief History of Humankind&lt;/a&gt; by
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ynharari.com&#34;&gt;Yuval Noah Harari&lt;/a&gt; and what a read it has been. It was long but the wisdom I gathered is baffling. I am very sceptical when famous people like Elon Musk and Bill Gates recommend a book but I did read this one and it has been an eye-opener. There is one topic which Harari talks about a lot and that is Capitalism. And in this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll see how too much of it is ruining our life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hopelessly Hopeful</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/hopelessly-hopeful/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 00:38:30 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/hopelessly-hopeful/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hope is the remedy world advocates to all the problems in life. How could ever being optimistic be a bad thing? I am a firm believer that optimism can solve almost all our problems, but recently I found out that maybe sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s okay to lose hope. Excess of anything is not good so is true with hope. If you ever become so hopelessly hopeful about an event happening you will overpower your intelligence and instinct and stay in limbo wondering about things that might never happen.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If the Crow Knew When to Stop</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/if-the-crow-knew-when-to-stop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2020 19:45:07 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/if-the-crow-knew-when-to-stop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We all know the story of the clever crow who used stones to get access to deep water in the earthen pot but what if I say that it&amp;rsquo;s not the complete story? What if it was the utopic version of an utter disaster? And his cleverness the cause of his death?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/assets/img/crow1.png&#34; alt=&#34;The crow who couldn&amp;rsquo;t stop&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The crow, albeit clever, and with a good intension started dropping stones in the pot. When he saw the water level rise he was ecstatic. He was very thirsty but now that was not important.
The adrenalin rush of having used his brain to get access to something that no one else could was giving him joy. He was enjoying himself and then he obsessed and here is his downfall.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Instant Liking vs Gradual Appreciation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/instant-liking-vs-gradual-appreciation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 22:45:42 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/instant-liking-vs-gradual-appreciation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is highly underestimated how much importance we put in instant likeness. We value what we like naturally. This might not be a bad thing per se but we ought to understand what this method of decision making brings with it. We all have known by now that there are no silver bullets in life and that holds for this behaviour of ours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve observed that the things that have given me longer-lasting happiness were things which I didn&amp;rsquo;t like at the first glace. Sound very weird, I know but I have examples from my own life that I&amp;rsquo;ll share. I&amp;rsquo;m forced to believe that the deliberate persistence and hard work we do towards anything can give birth to liking and that lasts more than our instant infatuation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Judging Is Easy Repentance Is Hard</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/judging-is-easy-repentance-is-hard/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 20:46:17 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/judging-is-easy-repentance-is-hard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are faster than a flash when we judge and slower than a snail when we accept mistakes. It&amp;rsquo;s been clearly understood by every sane person that judging is not right. We can only judge what we truly know and we truly know nothing. Less we know about ourself and lesser about anyone else. Then why is it so easy to judge?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Daniel_Kahneman&#34;&gt;Daniel Kahneman&lt;/a&gt; explains in his book &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uqXVAo7dVRU&#34;&gt;Thinking fast and slow&lt;/a&gt; we have two types of thought processes, one which is fast and automatic and the other which is slow and logical. They both have their place and should be used for the right job. We, humans, are lazy and we let the automatic and fast mind direct us the majority of the times. We look and make a judgement without waiting for the slow and logical mind to think about the background. This is a deep-rooted habit pattern as our ancestors were required to make quick decisions. It was a do or die situation but things have changed. Today we are not always in a perilous situation and can take time to stop and reason but it takes conscious practice to fix this.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Letter to Myself</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/a-letter-to-myself/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 01:08:54 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/a-letter-to-myself/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dear Ankit,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know that you are doing great in your life. The numbers are moving fast, the numbers of age, money and mistakes. I also congratulate you for all the hardships and struggles that you have overcome. Come on, I know you want to believe that it was nothing and people have worse and I agree. But that won&amp;rsquo;t mean that what you have achieved was easy. Applaud for your efforts even when many of them might have failed. Thank yourself for trying out new things and having the courage to work on your inner self with the highest priority.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>No Fortune for a Penny</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/no-fortune-for-a-penny/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2020 07:46:26 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/no-fortune-for-a-penny/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The title can mean different things to different people. For me, the only fortune is my time and love. My firm belief is that we love without expectations and I am the one who needs my love the most.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/no-fortune.png&#34; alt=&#34;No fortune for a penny quote&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all have limited energy on any given day and to invest it on someone who doesn&amp;rsquo;t give a damn about you is not a great way to spend it. I love you and I always will and that&amp;rsquo;s not going to change. But if what you bring on the table is selfishness and only concern about yourself, that&amp;rsquo;s a bad vibe. I am there for you when you need me and time gets hard and I&amp;rsquo;ve always been. But I&amp;rsquo;m not going to run after you, chase you and be constantly present, to be drained of my energy. I&amp;rsquo;m going to prioritize my peace and work on being happy myself first before I help anyone else. And if this hurts your feeling, fuck you!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Your Likes Can Tell</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/what-your-likes-can-tell/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 23:18:44 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/what-your-likes-can-tell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I pondered about my likes and then about the likes of some of my closest people. It soon dawned upon me that we don&amp;rsquo;t like much. I would challenge you to take one minute pause and think of 3 things you like? I&amp;rsquo;m confident that you are going to have a hard time listing even three of them. When someone like me tries to itemize them, they come up with travel, sleep and hangout(~hangover).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Happy Lives</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/happy-lives/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 22:13:05 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/happy-lives/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A happy couple was living in the fast-moving city of Bangalore. They would work hard every day in the cubicle. They took pride in what they did but there were days when nothing seemed right. All the efforts they put felt useless. While there were days when everything looked perfect and today was such a day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They have bought their first car. Working in a day job, living in a big city and owning a car seems like a dream for a middle-class family. And yes, of course, it includes putting in sick leaves on a lazy day, exploring the best brews in the town and going for a drive to the one favourite Maggie shop.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meaningful Questions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/meaningful-question/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 00:14:30 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/meaningful-question/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Question is undoubtedly the most powerful tool in the quiver of an inquisitive person. It is like a shovel using which we dig the dirt of ignorance and try to understand reality. It is also the torch we point towards the pit to better see in the darkness of falsehood. It is the chisel we use to carve our own personality. The way we question reality, nature and anything around, shapes our complete being. Buddha asked if sickness, old age and death would reach him? Newton asked why the apple fell down from the tree? A child asked why the star shines and how is there water inside the coconut?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Song of the Mountain and the Sea</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/the-song-of-the-mountain-and-the-sea/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 10:54:47 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/the-song-of-the-mountain-and-the-sea/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While you climb the mountain, &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
I tread the beach. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
While you pick the flower, &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
I clear the weed. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
While you protect me from the cold, &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
I fight the heat. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
While you shower the love, &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
I make the ends meet. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
While you see the stars, &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
I like to sleep. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
While you touch my arms, &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
I kiss your lips. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
While you push me forward, &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
I don&amp;rsquo;t let you fall deep. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
While you snap at me, &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
I sound the bleep. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
While you clean the house, &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
I clear utensils. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
While you sing the prayer, &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
I turn the beads. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
While you go to work, &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
I stay amiss, &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
While you suffer the pain, &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
I feel trist. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
While you instil discipline, &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
I spoil the kids. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
While you play the music, &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
I do the leads. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
While you do your hairs, &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
I find the clips. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
While you fight the tears, &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
I kill the pricks. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
While you&amp;rsquo;re with me, &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;ll always be me! :) &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Checking if My Cats Have Returned</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/checking-if-my-cats-have-returned/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 11:20:03 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/checking-if-my-cats-have-returned/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My life was marching on its comfortable path every day when some kittens showed up in my balcony. I would give milk to their mother, try to touch the kittens only when the mom was not there and keep smiling. The kittens grew fast and now they run and play. Only one thing hasn&amp;rsquo;t changed their mission to not come near me and my desire to hold the soft fur balls. It&amp;rsquo;s been almost perfect but perfect doesn&amp;rsquo;t last long. Things seem so perfect at times but then again in this world only change is permanent.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Forgive</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/why-forgive/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 11:19:48 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/why-forgive/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I visited Nandi Hill, a very beautiful place with clouds below your eyes. Small hills rising above the clouds as if cutting through them. If not for those hills the sky feels like another sea of white foam and water. I love to travel and I love it even more so for the insights and observations we make when travelling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time the wisdom is about forgiveness. It&amp;rsquo;s even stranger when I think what made me think about forgiveness and it was rudeness. Have you ever wondered why Jesus never confronted Judas even when he was well aware of what was going to happen? Or why Ram never had any hard feeling for Kaikeyi when she sends him to exile for no wrong? Or why Yusuf even as a king forgave his brothers for the years of suffering they brought upon him?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Extra Mile</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/the-extra-mile/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 10:23:41 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/the-extra-mile/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I look back to the things I&amp;rsquo;ve done I feel so selfish. I know there has to be a line between not doing anything to giving away your everything but now that I see I wish I could have done a little more. We are all born alone and we are destined to die that way. The only time we can be with someone is in between these two stations. I want to stop being so concerned and know that the journey is short and people will depart for their destination and we will not be together sometime very soon. This sense of ending brings so much gratitude in me which I want to express. This is for all the people who walk in that extra mile just be with me and help me. There is no one as important as you in my life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Hold the High</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/dont-hold-the-high/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2018 23:59:06 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/dont-hold-the-high/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Who doesn&amp;rsquo;t like the day when we are all high and happy? It is in such moments we feel complete and so satisfied. I&amp;rsquo;m glad that I&amp;rsquo;ve had those days in my life. But there is something else which follows just after this high and it&amp;rsquo;s the desire to hold it. We just want to stay in the same state and hold on to it and never let it go. Do we really think that we can do that? Just let things be. When it&amp;rsquo;s sunshine bath yourself in sun and when it&amp;rsquo;s rainy bath yourself in rain.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do You Need Anything?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/do-you-need-anything/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 13:29:22 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/do-you-need-anything/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I ask this question so frequently to myself and the answers vary between I don&amp;rsquo;t know and I&amp;rsquo;ve everything. Just take a brief moment to think how blessed that moment is when you are able to say that you are happy with what you have? I firmly believe that I&amp;rsquo;m very lucky and I&amp;rsquo;ve a lot that many people don&amp;rsquo;t. But you can also say that I don&amp;rsquo;t have so much that other people have? I don&amp;rsquo;t care though, really. I do care sometimes but then I know it&amp;rsquo;s ok as I&amp;rsquo;ve more than I need.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trust Issues</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/trust-issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 01:00:53 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/trust-issues/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A dog when he comes to you despite that fact that he has been hurt by hundreds of other human beings is trust. I have a notion of perfect trust where the slate is clean with no scratches and existing chalk dust. In the real world which is not possible. We all have scars and scratches in the form of heartbreak and broken trust. Does this mean we stop trusting?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Is Meditation?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/what-is-meditation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 11:36:28 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/what-is-meditation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have asked this question so many times. At times I feel that I understand what it is and at other, I don&amp;rsquo;t. This time I planned to write down what I understand about meditation and maintain a record and refer back to this in future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have a monkey mind, as
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Mingyur Rinpoche&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
calls it. It likes to talk and gossip and keep suggesting things based on its likes and dislikes. When we forget that we are not our thoughts and become the slave to whatever we think bad things can happen. Only when we realize that thoughts are just a form of suggestions, mostly based on past experiences and survival needs, we can free ourself from the slavery. When you know that you are not the thought you avoid being influenced by it and let it be. Our monkey mind has one very bad habit that it loves to work and solve hard problems. When we don&amp;rsquo;t have any real problem in our life it will try to exaggerate the small ones and try to solve them. Mingyur suggests that we need to make friends with our monkey mind and give him work. He has to do some work, the question is either we give him or he chooses what to work on. When we decide to employ the monkey mind and give him work we are his boss and things start to fall in place. And the best work to give to our monkey mind is meditation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Importance of Truth in Relationships</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/importance-of-truth-in-relationship/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 00:30:43 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/importance-of-truth-in-relationship/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A relationship should be one where you&amp;rsquo;re not afraid and have the courage to speak the truth. Not with an intention to hurt but with an understanding that it&amp;rsquo;s ok to be wrong. With a confidence that the person will accept you and understand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You acknowledge how bad it can feel when you speak your heart out but you know you&amp;rsquo;re appreciated. You feel the depth of hurt it will cause and you make sure not to ease any of the pain. The only resolve that you make is not to cause such a suffering again, for in speaking truth the pain is more yours than theirs. The only thing you expect from them is faith that&amp;rsquo;ll you improve.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Her Side of the Story</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/her-side-of-the-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2018 21:54:56 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/her-side-of-the-story/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I shared &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/blog/when-i-hurt&#34;&gt;my side of the story&lt;/a&gt;. How I feel the pain and cheated but I know mistakes were made from my side as well. I might not be able to do all the justice to her feelings but trying to say everything that she made me known.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t want to write much concrete details here but the lines below should be enough to tell you my flaws.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You told them everything, &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
And called me names,&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
But did you forget about your games?&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When I Hurt</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/when-i-hurt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2018 11:23:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/when-i-hurt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not hurt, not most of the times or so I say to myself but when I hurt it hurts real bad. There are very few things and very few people who can hurt me. I&amp;rsquo;m also aware that it&amp;rsquo;s I who is giving them this heart-shattering power, yet I do. Some of them know to value and keep my heart safe while others juggle is down every alley.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I&amp;rsquo;m hurting again and this is a hurt of a long lost love. I guess I&amp;rsquo;m over her but only my heart knows what&amp;rsquo;s the truth. The problem I guess here is with my expectations and I forgot that if you love someone that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean that the other person will love you the same. If you remember from your experience you will also know this. In your school days when the person, you called your best friend named someone else as their best friend. It felt bad, but that&amp;rsquo;s how reality works. Today if someone wise would have to say the same thing he would say, &amp;ldquo;If you are a vegetarian and won&amp;rsquo;t eat a lion, that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean the lion won&amp;rsquo;t eat you as well.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Men Without Women Review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/men-without-women-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 12:15:05 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/men-without-women-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This was the first book by &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Haruki_Murakami&#34;&gt;Murakami&lt;/a&gt; which I read. There are certain characteristics of his writing that I would like to bring up. This will help us appreciate and understand his work better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, Murakami is a great observer. He talks about daily affairs in such light and detail that you will wonder whether you are living life in the right way. His stories don&amp;rsquo;t need any fancy setting or place. All he uses is an old rusty car or a simple bedroom with a perfectly common ceiling. Secondly, you can find him using vivid dreams and imagery. His dreams are very real and you will find him using different creatures like cat, fish and snakes to add some tinge to the story. Thirdly, there is a sense of enigma in his writing he makes you ask questions and then takes you on an incomplete journey to find the answers. I personally love this as he gives us enough context about the riddle we are trying to solve but no more. We are all free to come to our own conclusions as we see fit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Rising Radicalism</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/the-rising-radicalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 12:08:39 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/the-rising-radicalism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are all opinionated and most of the time these opinions are not our own. They are thrusted into our consciousness by the people around us, the media and the general ideology of the society. I believe opinions are neutral just like smartphones which are neither bad nor good on their own. There are other sources of opinion like from books, family and friends. What I&amp;rsquo;m trying to get at it is that there are varied sources of opinions and it differs for each individual.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Threads of Life</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/threads-of-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2018 01:10:48 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/threads-of-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We all know so many people around and we think and treat each of them differently. We have different roles to play. I think the thread and the life are very much related. I find them a lot more similar than distinct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone is connected to every other person via a thread so fragile yet so powerful. Consider a man seeing a woman suffering from a severe chronic disease. They don&amp;rsquo;t know if they will even see the next day. Both the person try to live happily and a very simple and drama free life. What is happening here is that the thread is always fragile and in this relation the parties realize this. They realize how delicate and uncertain life is. Just like a bubble in the water, which burst into nothingness without any warnings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Zen of a Happy Life</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/the-zen-of-a-happy-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2017 22:48:22 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/the-zen-of-a-happy-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When things are good, express gratitude.
When things are bad, practice patience.
When things are average, show staisfaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Situtations can be either good, bad or average. I know this might look like I am judging how things are. I also know great people talk about equanimity in all situations. I&amp;rsquo;m not there yet, though I want to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tend to get sad at times just like every other human being. I know it is a part of the life. Just like the darkness gives meaning to the light, the sorrow gives meaning to the happiness. I think, the most important things to learn in life is to learn handling rejections.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the Matter of Love</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/on-the-matter-of-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2017 02:41:29 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/on-the-matter-of-love/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not very romantic by profession, which is engineering, but if this post gets you somewhere, believe me, it&amp;rsquo;s not me. Have you felt the tingling of heart in the presence of a certain someone? The tingling that sends blood rushing throughout your body. When your veins are screaming the constant melody of your heart. If you know this feeling, you will know what I&amp;rsquo;m saying. When being close to that person makes your mouth go dry, no it is not your subconscious intentions(preparations) for the upcoming kiss. It is the heat that he feels from your subtle presence. You must have seen her speak so much, but when the season is of love, you will hardly hear her utter words.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Attempt to Live</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/an_attempt_to_live/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2017 01:00:06 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/an_attempt_to_live/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been trying to define life for a very long time. All this started when I felt pain for the first time, I don&amp;rsquo;t remember the reason for my pain, but I was suffering. I was trying to see through it and had some realizations. When I am ill I can see that I&amp;rsquo;m in pain and my body is not working as it should, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t affect my mind. I can still choose to smile. At moments others can&amp;rsquo;t even tell if I am unwell. The only way they could know is to see my running nose, find me sneezing or touch my face and see that I&amp;rsquo;m burning. There have been other times when I&amp;rsquo;ve been in emotional pain. These feelings are yet more subtle. It feels like everything is fine around but the mind is not at rest. It is unsettled about something. On closer inspection, I saw that whenever my mind is disturbed I have a series of thoughts, uncontrolled, which leads me to all the suffering. But that was about suffering and not feeling good, but what of life? How do you define life?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Productive Day</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/a_productive_day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2017 22:44:15 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/a_productive_day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some days are better than some other days&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is rightly said that some days are better than others. Today was one of such days. I haven&amp;rsquo;t achieved a lot though but yes it is a lot better than the unproductive streak that I had since last few weeks. Yesterday I gave some thought to uncertainty in life and how it affects my decision making, maybe that helped me get some clarity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facing the Uncertain</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/facing_the_uncertain/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 21:19:30 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/facing_the_uncertain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I wonder if you too are afraid of uncertainties? It is very easy to dream but the hard work it takes to make it a reality is not insignificant. The fear that things may not turn out as I think they should, stops me from putting in the hard work. Is this an excuse? I get thoughts that wait for the right idea where success is guaranteed. This idea is very lucrative and saves me from doing any real work right now. Isn&amp;rsquo;t this situation similar to the saying:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Beginning</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/the_beginning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 19:30:24 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/the_beginning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;October is ending today and winter is at the door. I cannot say &lt;em&gt;Winter is coming&lt;/em&gt; as now it&amp;rsquo;s more like a trademark. Its been a while since I&amp;rsquo;ve been home. Hyderabad is good to me but there is no place which can be like home. The sense of security and peace just by seeing your father and mother cannot be expressed. I feel like I am once again a child like those good old days. Those days where we used to get hurt a little, think a little less and smile a bit more. If I had to stay somewhere that would be my in my moms lap and under my fathers eyes. I&amp;rsquo;ve named the title as &lt;strong&gt;The Beginning&lt;/strong&gt; but I don&amp;rsquo;t know what&amp;rsquo;s to be written. So I just thought there&amp;rsquo;s no better way to start then express my gratitude to all, who touched my life and gave a difference essence to it. Last week I travelled to Kerala, which is titled as God&amp;rsquo;s own country. It was a journey that spanned over 7 days and it was really nice to be there.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/hello/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/hello/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;im hello md&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
